LOSAUNNE WHITE

Experienced analytics engineer with knowledge in automation, data accuracy, and efficiency. Capable of conceptualizing functional and business requirements and translating to an engineering framework. Proficient in creating data pipelines with a background in software engineering practices. Continual learner with interest in pushing my skills forward.

CONTACT

losaunne.white@gmail.com

Salt Lake City, UT 👂

(801) 513-7403

linkedin.com/in/losaunne-white in

github.com/losaunne 🌓

SKILLS

Python (numpy, jupyter, pandas, matplotlib, scikit-learn)

SQL Git

Docker

Airflow

Segment Looker

Looker Snowflake

dbt

GCP

Power BI Talend

Linux R

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Mathematics University of Utah Salt Lake City, Utah

COURSES

Data Engineering Zoomcamp DataTalksClub, in progress

Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification Coursera, February 2018

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Data Science Analyst

Adobe, Lehi, Utah

April 2019 - August 2021

- Decreased processing time of existing daily and hourly Python and SQL processes by 60%, increasing reliability and deliverability by implementing error and success logging
- Led discovery work on integration of new data sources into our data warehouse, developing a standard operating procedure and training team members
- Built Python and R packages for interfacing with SQL Server, used by 20+ people across teams
- Collaborated to analyze over 1T data points using a linear regression algorithm in R, communicating methodology and accuracy to journalists and executives
- Developed Python models to deliver new insights to executives, sales teams, and journalists
- Implemented a documentation and reproducibility standard, pushing the team to dedicate 10% time to documentation using Git

Data Analytics Engineer - Consultant

Ollie. Remote

November 2020 - February 2021

- Led project from architecture to integration of a new data source using dbt and Snowflake ETL tools, before creating dashboard in Looker used for forecasting by marketing leadership

Data Analytics Engineer - Consultant

Lovevery, Remote

November 2019 - March 2020

- Recommended and implemented a custom marketing solution in Python, algorithmically transforming data from Google Analytics before loading into data warehouse

Data & Insights Product Manager

Backcountry, Park City, Utah

August 2018 - April 2019

- Guided a team of six data engineers to support long-term company and team initiatives by prioritizing a robust backlog while managing dozens of stakeholder expectations
- Scheduled and monitored ETL jobs using Talend and Cron
- Designed an updated architecture for primary fact and dimension tables to better accommodate business requirements, cutting ETL processing time down by 60%
- Scoped data and analytics requirements across the organization for an updated enterprise BI tool before successfully pitching Looker to leadership and driving implementation
- Decreased reporting time by 80% by automating a daily process requiring multiple disparate data sources in Python

Senior Marketing Analyst

Backcountry, Park City, Utah

August 2016 - August 2018

- Productionalized hourly and daily ETL processes in Python using multiple third-party APIs to automate reporting, leading to a 90% time savings
- Authored and productionalized a new process for consuming over 1M rows of raw clickstream data into a summary table in our data warehouse using Python and SQL, allowing for deep analyses to optimize marketing tactics
- Developed a custom algorithm using Python and SQL to make informed adjustments to the \$50MM annual marketing budget and provide insight into customer journey
- Used multivariate linear regression on thousands of data points to determine acceptable output levels across different dimensionality combinations